"[...] which is..."
"...the greatest keyboard
"...of all time."
Oh ho, PewDiePie.
You just had to say that,
...didn't you?
About three months ago,
...PewDiePie announced his
...latest product collaboration,
...a mechanical keyboard
...and a mouse that I didn't buy
...because I don't care about mouse.
Now, now,
...naturally as a
...19-plus-2-year-old,
...I was pretty interested.
And by 'interested',
...I meant I rushed to the nearest internet browser,
...flipping slammed in the website
...and mashed in my bank account details
...and sat waiting patiently for the board to arrive.
Fast forward about two weeks,
...my keyboard arrives,
...my excitement is immeasurable,
...and my fingers...
I think they're ready.
Now, you might be wondering,
"Glarses, you use custom keyboards all day."
"Why are you excited about this one?"
"Also, you said you got this keyboard three months ago."
"Why are you only making this video now-"
Well, I'll tell you.
I'm excited, not only because
...PewDiePie said this about the keyboard.
Roll the clip:
...but because of the incredible,
...and I mean
...the INCREDIBLE
...product listing
...that Ghost Keyboards gave for this board.
[clears throat]
This is my favorite part.
Right.
[sighs]
And this, ladies and gentlemen,
...is what I call 'shooting yourself in the foot',
...because for the remainder of this video,
...I'm going to purely evaluate this keyboard
...based on the description they gave.
Here.
We.
Go.
The case is high-profile
...with relatively thin uniform bezels
...and curved edges,
...a matte black finish,
...a bunch of logos,
...a recessed USB port,
...and most importantly,
...four rectangular rubber feet.
The external finish is fine.
It's not quite
...Korean sparkly,
...but it is grainy,
...but consistently grainy.
So... it's alright.
Unfortunately, they decided to
...throw away all that consistency internally,
...choosing instead to sport
...scratches,
...uh, peeling,
...very obvious machining marks,
...which confused me because I-
...I thought this was a 'premium keyboard'.
This is a tray-mount case,
...meaning the PCB and the plates
...screw into mounting posts on the bottom of the case.
But before you decide to throw in
...your aftermarket PCBs and plates,
...don't.
It doesn't support them.
Coupled with the aluminium plate,
...you have yourself exactly one firm typing experience,
...which is admittedly the same as most pre-bought keyboards,
...so...
I'm not not gonna call this premium,
...but this is very obviously
...a $50 aftermarket case, so...
[klaxon]
...I'm really hoping there's $180 worth of value
...in the rest of this keyboard.
Spoilers:
There's not.
Moving on to their premium Cherry MX switches,
...of which there was a choice of
...Reds, Blues and Browns.
And I chose Browns obviously.
[chuckles]
Now, ignoring my own biases,
...these RGB Cherry MX Browns
...are very scratchy,
...which does not at all help accentuate
...their very small tactile bump.
Now, I know, before you say it,
...this isn't just a case of
"Cherry MX Browns bad!"
In the last year I've picked up
...retooled Browns and HyperGlide Browns
...that are distinctly smoother than these.
These also have incredibly bad spring prints
So, uh...
[klaxon]
Yeah, 'premium'.
Here's a sound test:
As per their description,
...the PewDiePie keyboard comes with:
...so...
This should be good.
Oh...
No, no, no, no, no...
I don't believe this.
Okay.
Please...
[sighs]
Oh, no...
No, no, no, no...
Enhance!
ENHANCE!
[slams table]
THEY FORGOT THE LUBE!
These
...unclipped
...plate mount stabilizers
...are bone-dry.
Like, they-
[sighs]
[chuckles]
There's these little droplets of lube
...they put on the stabilizer housing inserts,
...so...
...it's
...technically lubed,
...because there's lube on it,
...but man.
It does absolutely nothing
...to increase smoothness or reduce rattle.
These are among the scratchiest,
...rattliest stabilizers
...I have ever had the displeasure of using,
So...
Yeah.
[klaxon]
Okay.
First...
I think the wavy design is really nice.
I really like the wavy design on the keycaps
And I didn't notice it at first,
...but the waves on the keycap
...actually connect
...at the end
...and beginning of another keycap on the bottom row
...which I thought was just...
[chef's kiss]
I thought that was really cool, um...
Okay.
However,
...the legends on the wavy keycaps are inconsistent
...in both thickness and positioning.
It looks like they just
...slapped it onto the keycap.
And there's this weird saturation disparity
...from the top of the keycap to the sides.
Like,
...when you see it you-
...you can't unsee it anymore.
They also bleed light like crazy,
...especially through that spacebar.
The main alphas are a lot better,
...their legends are a lot crisper
...and more consistent in their thickness and positioning.
These are a bit thicker than your
...normal gamery keycaps.
They have a nice subtle grippiness.
But they have the same problem
...that a lot of these cheap doubleshot [shinethrough] keycaps have.
In terms of the connecting 'O'-type letters and numbers
...where you can see it doesn't connect properly
...so you get these kind of, like,
...dark spots
...which look kind of inconsistent
...when you shine those LEDs through them.
The grippy washed keycaps are...
...grippy.
[chuckles]
I- You know,
...it's got that kind of
...grippy rubber texture
...and the actual engraved waves
...also adds to a bit of that.
I'd say the keycaps on this board are a bit of a step up
...from your normal gaming keyboard,
...but it's still like a...
...$25 aftermarket keycap set.
Yeah, I'm still waiting for the rest of that
...$180 in value.
The Felix board PCB
...comes with a whole host of features like...
...RGB and...
...Bluetooth wireless 5.0
...with a 2,000 amp-
It's not even funny.
No, I'm laughing.
I like Bluetooth.
I- I love Bluetooth.
And it was really straightforward next to my computer.
This keyboard also has
...per-key RGB
...via SMD LEDs,
...which can be adjusted to do a range of...
...RGB things [chuckles]
...like... static colours
...and breathing colours
...and whatever the heck this is called.
And oh, I can turn it off.
Lovely.
However,
...north-facing LEDs
...means that you're going to run into interference
...with your Cherry Profile keycaps, so...
...no, kids,
...don't put your GMKs on here.
There's a bunch of built-in hotkeys and shortcuts
...like...
'Menu'
...and onboard macro functionality,
...which was an absolute pain to use.
There is no software support,
...the booklet explaining all of this stuff
...sucks,
...there is no QMK support,
...no VIA support,
...so...
...in every sense
...a very lacking PCB.
This is a
...$50 GK61
...with a $50 aluminium aftermarket case
...which I paid
...$230 for.
Yay.
Unfortunately,
...instead of getting an ultra-premium keyboard
...without the ultra-premium price tag,
...you get an ultra-standard keyboard
...with an ultra-bloated price-
"Hey!"
Who are you?
"You..."
"...are being WAY too harsh on this keyboard!"
- You know, seriously,
- "It's a prebuilt keyboard."
- ...who are you and how did you get into my house?
- "You can’t find them with"
"...decent stabilizers."
"They're all trash."
"That's such a low blow."
"Oh."
"Okay."
"But that must be like one of those expensive-"
$100.
[winces]
You okay?
"Okay, okay, okay..."
"But you can't build an all-aluminium-"
"What is that?"
O- Oh, this?
Yeah, it's just my...
...PewDiePie-inspired keyboard.
Keycaps with red Japanese sub-legends
...to match PewDiePie's weeaboos.
It also has clipped new PCB mount stabilizers,
...a carbon fiber plate,
...Novelkeys Creams,
...and...
...a red case.
"Right, but how much does that cost?"
About $180.
[winces]
"But..."
"...that has a low-profile case."
"PewDiePie keyboard has a high-profile case,"
"...so..."
Oh, like this?
This high-profile
...and denser case
...of the stainless steel weight?
Yeah, just add
...$20 to $25.
[winces]
"But- Okay. I want..."
"Hot swap!"
"And RGB!"
"And- And-"
"Bluetooth!"
Awesome.
Just get a GK61X PCB,
...add an extra $15.
[winces]
"Cherry MX Browns!"
"I want Cherry MX Browns!"
"Just like the PewDiePie keyboard!"
For sure, yeah. Just...
...subtract $20.
NARRATOR: It's super effective!
Right.
At the end of the day,
...this is still a keyboard
...that will do keyboard things for you.
So if you really love those
...wavy wavy keycaps
...or you are a
...die-hard PewDiePie fan, then...
Go for it.
But...
...honestly,
...this is a pretty small PP keyboard.
Bad 👏
Meme 👏